Nathan Roberts

Résumé

Introduction

I'm Nathan Roberts, a product designer focusing on a human-centered design approach with a curiosity for technical details and a passion for growth. My best work is done in collaboration with others.

Since graduating college in 2006, I've been building digital experiences small and large. I launched and managed a small e-commerce business, then joined Oakley as an Interaction Designer. Later, I led the Interaction Design team for Oakley's digital experiences. Now I lead a product design team at Experian building the future of finance.

Contact

Email: nathan@nathanroberts.com

Web: http://nathanroberts.com

Phone: (309) 472-0156

Education

B.A., Communications
Bradley University
2006

Skills

Human-centered design with a focus on learning and iteration, front-end development (HTML, CSS/SCSS and JavaScript), code collaboration (Git/GitHub), some basic experience in Xcode and Android Studio.

Employment History

Experian, Product Design Lead (2017–present)

Collaborating with product and cross-functional teams to conduct user research, design prototypes, test, iterate and launch digital products.

Oakley, Interaction Design Lead (2015 – 2016)

Designed and built e-commerce and marketing experiences for Oakley.com. Designed native mobile apps like Radar Pace, Surf Report and Mad Science.

Oakley, Interaction Designer (2013 – 2014)

Designed e-commerce flows, shopping experiences and marketing pages. Built and maintained a platform for non-commerce experiences with Craft CMS, Amazon S3 and MediaTemple.

Uftring Marketing Group, Designer (2012-2013)

Managed 5+ auto dealership websites, designed and coded marketing-driven landing pages, designed social media campaigns for sales events.

Haberfeld, Consultant (2010-2011)

Evaluated client application of customer acquisition and growth strategies, reported findings on field research to improve training and increase sales.

V Gallery, Designer and Developer (2008–2010)

Designed, coded, launched and managed a

Magento-based e-commerce business selling

<\$100K/yr of digital and physical products.